<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20250702</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC1568273</id><infon key="license">NO-CC CODE</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC1568273</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">6499798</infon><infon key="fpage">141</infon><infon key="journal-title">Environmental Health Perspectives</infon><infon key="lpage">146</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schuler;given-names:R L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hardin;given-names:B D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Niemeier;given-names:R W</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Booth;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hazelden;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Piccirillo;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Smith;given-names:K</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">57</infon><infon key="year">1984</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Results of testing fifteen glycol ethers in a short-term in vivo reproductive toxicity assay.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>94</offset><text>Fifteen glycol ethers were investigated for their potential to cause adverse reproductive toxic effects using an in vivo mouse screening bioassay. Pregnant mice were orally dosed once per day on days 7 through 14 of gestation at concentrations causing 0 to 41% maternal mortality. Reproductive endpoints included pup survival in utero (percent of live litters/pregnant survivors), pup perinatal and postnatal survival (number of live pups per litter, number of dead pups per litter, and pup survival to 2.5 days of age), and pup body weight statistics (weight at birth and weight at 2.5 days of age). The study was conducted in two phases: a dose range-finding phase using nonpregnant female mice, and a definitive reproductive phase using time-mated mice. The range-finding phase sought to identify, for each chemical, the maternal LD10 as the target dose. However, based upon reproductive phase results, such an exact dose was impractical to achieve. Thus, a range from the LD5 to the LD20 was considered a sufficient challenge dose that would not affect results due to high mortality, i.e., greater than the LD20. Glycol ethers were assigned to groups having different priorities for further testing based upon whether a sufficient challenge dose was administered and the degree of effects recorded for each chemical.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS)</text></passage></document>
</collection>